Yves Ngenzi

+250791166123

ngenziyves1@gmail.com https://github.com/Yxn16a

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am an electrical/software engineer with five years of experience in software and hardware testing and development. Highly skilled software development professional bringing enormous talents for software design, development, and integration. Offering advanced knowledge of in-demand programming languages.

EDUCATION

Abilene Christian University

Abilene, TX

Major: Electrical Engineering, B.S.E (in-major GPA: 3.76)

August 2017 - May 2021

Awards, and Honors: University Scholar award (2021), Outstanding Sophomore Engineer (2019).

EXPERIENCE

Rwanda Space Agency

Kigali, Rwanda

Software Development Engineer, Intern

June 2022 - August 2022

Developed a flood and landslides alert mobile application using Node.js, React Native, CSS, HTML5, React

Collaborated with landslide experts to acquire data that the landslide and flood alert mobile application uses

Documented the mobile application using Swagger and tested its back-end rest API using postman

Learn Programming Academy

Online

Java Programming Boot Camp, Participant

Sep 2021 - June 2022

Learned and built library management API using core Java, Java enterprise, and Spring Boot Framework

Developed backend employee management application using Spring Book

Learned and practiced Structured Query Language (SQL) with MySQL and PostgreSQL by cloning an Instagram database

Avanzar Interior Technologies

San Antonio, TX

Manufacturing/Controls Engineer, Intern

Jun 2021 - Sept 2021

Created, debugged, and migrated RS500 to Studio 5000 plc programs for headliners oven robots, created an Excel-based system to manage Tundra and Sequoia seat foam inventory which efficiently improved inventory management.

Google

San Antonio, TX

Google Hardware Product Sprint (HPS), Apprentice

Jun 2021 - August 2021

Created a product definition for a digital clock, developed its analog circuit schematic using Ki CAD software, layout its PCB following design guidelines, fabricated and assembled its board, and validated and tested the board

Nuclear Energy Experimental Testing Laboratory

Abilene, TX

Engineering research assistant, Intern

Aug 2019 - May 2021

Conducted thermal insulation testing at 700°C using thermocouples and PLC, created and managed insulation CAD models using both inventor and Vault, and reviewed drawing drafts of a molten salt nuclear reactor.

Fermilab/ Abilene Christian University

Batavia, IL

Engineering Research Assistant, Intern

May 2018 - Aug 2019

Assembled photomultiplier tube analog circuit boards, thermally tested the boards, and tested their impedance and power dispassion, analyzed their signal output using oscilloscopes and signal generators for proton spin research detectors.

PROJECTS

Node js early landslides warning rest API, Spring boot Employee management rest API, Spring boot library management rest API, and Node js Hills marketplace rest API.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: SQL, Java, C++, javascript, Verilog, R. Software: ORCAD, Ki CAD, Autodesk Inventor, Vault, Studio5000, Maple, Spring boot, react js, node js, CSS, HTML5, bootstrap, and react native.